Profile

A Senior Software Engineer with a passion for problem solving with around 8 years experience in front end technologies (Angular, Ionic, Cordova and related libraries) along with Java Spring MVC experience of 1 year, aspiring to take on a more challenging role as a Technical Lead.

Extensive experience in Design and architecture of frontend web applications and hybrid mobile applications.

Worked at client site Randolph Brooks Federal Credit Union (RBFCU, San Antonio, Texas USA) for 2.5 years in similar technologies and led a team of front end developers for last 2 years.

Extensive domain knowledge in core banking and account processing solutions. Domain knowledge in Deposit accounts, loan applications, Checks and other security/privacy related knowledge in Finance or banking.

USA B1/B2 (Business Visitor) Visa ready.

Canada Business/Visitor Visa ready.

Skills

Front End Technical Lead

- Implemented best practices and Clean coding standards for Front end application (10-12 resources) team (Angular/HTML/CSS/SASS)
- Code Review for frontend team, worked as a gate keeper for Code merge.
- Design and create base Architecture for Frontend(FE) application.
- Release management using CodePush and AppCentre for Hybrid Mobile applications using lonic and Cordova
- PBR meeting to discuss sprint work with PO and Scrum Master
- Discussion with BU/stakeholders on requirements and changes needed to be implemented
- Prod and QA build release for testing using Jenkins
- Co-ordinated with UX team for feasibility and design of new pages.
- Worked with backend team to decide data contract and data needed in API
- Reviewed Unit test cases and suggested changes.

Developer

- Worked on latest Angular Framework (7.x and 8.x)
- State management and consuming service API using Redux framework (NGRX library)
- Developed responsive web pages using HTML and SASS

- Developed IONIC Framework UI pages for Native mobile app and build using Cordova
- Implemented native Ionic-Cordova plugins for Camera, contacts, QR code scanner etc.
- Exposed API services built using Spring Restful services.
- Implemented performance improvement practices for Angular applications.
- E2E Testing using protractor and Unit test cases using Jasmine and Karma.

Experience

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER AT XORIANT, WORKING AS TECHNICAL LEAD FOR CLIENT – FEB 2020 TO TILL DATE Client: Citi Bank

<u>Data Trace</u> – is an application developed for conducting review of reported data and ongoing data quality review for accuracy of Data elements consumed by Key Management and Regulatory reports.

<u>Blueworks Client</u> – is an application build for maintaining all processes followed across Citi. The application helps to edit and follow a process that has been implemented.

Responsibilities – Both applications are built from scratch

Design and build the base architecture of the application with all necessary libraries and components needs to start development.

Design and develop application level features and components needed to complete functionality.

Providing technical guidance to team members and involved in discussion and suggestion with backend team for data contract, request and responses.

Working in Agile Scrum Development with demos and releases every two weeks in QA Env.

Code Review, QA Release, Unit test cases creation.

FRONT END DEVELOPMENT ANALYST, FISERV PUNE- OCT 2019 TO FEB 2020

Working in Technology Centre of Excellence (TechCoE) group in Fiserv.

FRONT END DEVELOPMENT LEAD, RBFCU (ONSITE FOR FISERV), SAN ANTONIO, TEXAS – OCT 2017 TO OCT 2019

Move Money – Move money is a in-house P2P (person to person) solution for RBFCU to transfer money using phone number or email id.

<u>Online Banking Redesign</u> – NetBranch Online was an existing net banking application which was redesigned using Angular, Angular material and other related technologies. Online banking had different features like Account Summary, opening a checking, savings and different type of accounts. Apply for Auto Loan, mortgage etc. The application has other features like check deposit and order checks etc. Existing application was built in Struts and JSP pages.

Hybrid Mobile application was built using Angular 7, Ionic and Cordova framework.

Responsive website was built using Angular 7, Angular Material for UI and SASS/CSS.

Projects developed in Agile Scrum Methodology, used Git hub for source control.

Key responsibilities:

Design and develop base architecture for fronted application.

Build framework as per standard for FE application.

Discuss with BU/stakeholders on requirements and changes needed to implement.

Assign task to developers for Sprint related work and assist in resolving issues related to code.

Develop and Unit test application pages in Angular/HTML/CSS.

Resolve Production issues on priority.

Code review and release management using CodePush and AppCentre for project.

FRONT END DEVELOPMENT ANALYST, RBFCU (ONSITE FOR FISERV), SAN ANTONIO, TEXAS – MAR 2017 TO OCT 2017

<u>Joint Account Owner</u> – The project provided a solution to open different type of Deposit Accounts and Certificates with a Joint Owner. This feature was not available in internet banking. Different role was assigned to Owner and joint Owner based upon the request.

Skills used: Developed responsive webpages in JSP, Spring MVC based architecture. Write controllers and service layer for opening an account and editing existing DB scripts to allow joint owners in system. Developed pages as per new design provided by UX team.

FRONT END DEVELOPMENT SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER, FISERV, PUNE – APR 2013 TO MAR 2017

State Advantage Management System (SAMS) – It is a web based application used to configure Statements, Loan Bills and Credit Cards fro clients. It provides functionality to add new clients, add configuration, modify existing clients and generate CSV files which are fed to SA to generate desired output. Application is a Single Page Application (SPA).

Travelled Onshore to capture requirements and create base architecture for building application from scratch. And again to setup and deploy application in UAT/Production.

<u>Virtual Archive</u>— is an application used to get e-statements, Tax statements or stock documents in a Physical CD/DVD or digital format from a third party vendors or individual broker dealers. It is a responsive web app for all platforms developed using AngularJS and BootStrap. SPA.

<u>PopMoney</u> – is an application used to make P2P payments or request using email or phone number of the person. It is SPA. It supports capability to link different bank accounts to single pop money profile and leverage these accounts for facilitating payments. It is responsive app for all platforms developed using AngularJS and BootStrap.

Key responsibilities:

Interacted with BU in order to capture requirements and study their exiting architectural design.

Developed end to end modules in AngularJS, Java Services and JS frameworks.

Write Unit test cases using Jasmine.

Education

Centre for Development of Advance Computing ACTS, Pune – Feb 2013

Bachelor of Engineering in Electronics and Tele-Comm, Amravati University - May 2012

References

Vaishali Dalvi (vdalvi@rbfcu.org)— WebTeam Manager, Randolph Brooks Federal Credit Union, San Antonio Texas

Rajashekhar Kandikayala (rkandikayala@rbfcu.org) – Vice President at RBFCU, San Antonio Texas

Vinod Mahajan – Vice President, Solutions Architecture, Barclays, Pune